<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ReferenceCards Version="0.04">
	<ReferenceCard>
		<Name>Ion Token</Name>
		<Text>This card explains the rules for an ion token and serves as a reference to remind players of it's effect.

Some card abilities, such as the &quot;Ion Cannon Turret&quot; Upgrade card, can cause a ship to receive an ion token.  A ship with an ion token assigned to it follows special rules during these phases:

* Planning Phase: The owner does not assign a maneuver dial to this ship.

* Activation Phase: The owner moves the ship as if it were assigned a white {1 straight} maneuver.  After executing this maneuver, remove all ion tokens from the ship.  It may perform actions as normal.

* Combat Phase: The ship may attack as normal.</Text>
	</ReferenceCard>
	<ReferenceCard>
		<Name>Boost Action</Name>
		<Text>This card explains the rules for performing a Boost action.  Ships with the {boost} icon in their action bar may perform a boost action.  To boost, follow these steps:

1.  Choose the {1 straight}, {1 bank left}, or {1 bank right} maneuver template.
2.  Set the maneuver template between the ship's front guides.
3.  Move the ship to the opposite end of the template and slide the rear guides of the ship into the template.

Performing a boost does not count as executing a maneuver.  A ship cannot boost if this would cause its base to overlap with another ship's base or an obstacle token.</Text>
	</ReferenceCard>
	<ReferenceCard>
		<Name>Bomb Tokens</Name>
		<Detail>(Seismic Charge and Proximity Mine)</Detail>
		<Text>The seismic charge and proximity mine tokens are bomb tokens.  Bomb tokens Detonate as described on their corresponding Upgrade cards, producing one of the following effects.

* Seismic Charge Token: When this bomb token detonates, each ship at Range 1 of the token suffers 1 damage.  Then discard this token.

* Proximity Mine Token: When this bomb token detonates, the ship that moved through or overlapped this token rolls 3 attack dice and suffers all damage {hit} and critical damage {crit} rolled.  Then discard this token.</Text>
	</ReferenceCard>
	<ReferenceCard>
		<Name>Bomb Tokens</Name>
		<Detail>(Seismic Charge and Proton Bomb)</Detail>
		<Text>Bomb tokens Detonate as described on their corresponding Upgrade cards, producing one of the following effects:

* Seismic Charge Token: When this bomb token detonates, each ship at Range 1 of the token suffers 1 damage.  Then discard this token.

* Proton Bomb Token: When this bomb token detonates, deal 1 faceup Damage card to each ship at Range 1 of the token.   Then discard this token.</Text>
	</ReferenceCard>
	<ReferenceCard>
		<Name>Bomb Tokens</Name>
		<Detail>(Ion Bomb and Conner Net)</Detail>
		<Text>The ion bomb and Conner net tokens are bomb tokens.  Bomb tokens Detonate as described on their corresponding Upgrade cards, producing one of the following effects:

* Ion Bomb Token: When this bomb token detonates, each ship at Range 1 of the token receives 2 ion tokens.  Then discard this token.

* Conner Net Token: When this bomb token detonates, the ship that moved through or overlapped this token suffers 1 damage, receives 2 ion tokens, and skips its &quot;Perform Action&quot; step.  Then discard this token.</Text>
	</ReferenceCard>
	<ReferenceCard>
		<Name>Bomb Tokens</Name>
		<Detail>(Ion Bomb and Cluster Mines)</Detail>
		<Text>The ion bomb and cluster mine tokens are bomb tokens.  Bomb tokens Detonate as described on their corresponding Upgrade cards, producing one of the following effects.

* Ion Bomb Token: When this bomb token detonates, each ship at Range 1 of the token receives 2 ion tokens.  Then discard this token.

* Cluster Mine Tokens: When one of these bomb tokens detonates, the ship that moved through or overlapped that token rolls 2 attack dice and suffers all damage {hit} rolled.  Then discard that token.</Text>
	</ReferenceCard>
	<ReferenceCard>
		<Name>Bomb Tokens</Name>
		<Detail>(Thermal Detonators and Conner Net)</Detail>
		<Text>The Thermal Detonator and Conner Net tokens are bomb tokens.  Bomb tokens Detonate as described on their corresponding Upgrade cards, producing one of the following effects:

* Thermal Detonators Token: When this bomb token detonates, each ship at Range 1 of the token suffers 1 damage and receives 1 stress token.  Then discard this token.

* Conner Net Token: When this bomb token detonates, the ship that moved through or overlapped this token suffers 1 damage, receives 2 ion tokens, and skips its &quot;Perform Action&quot; step.  Then discard this token.</Text>
	</ReferenceCard>
	<ReferenceCard>
		<Name>Cloak</Name>
		<Text>This card explains the rules for performing a Cloak action.  Ships with the {cloak} icon in their action bar may perform a cloak action.

When a ship performs the cloak action, place 1 cloak token near that ship.  A ship cannot perform the cloak action while it already has a cloak token.

The agility value of a ship with a cloak token is increased by 2.  While that ship has a cloak token, it cannot perform attacks.

Cloak tokens are not removed during the End phase.</Text>
	</ReferenceCard>
	<ReferenceCard>
		<Name>Decloak</Name>
		<Text>At the start of the Activation phase, after players have resolved all other abilities that trigger at the start of the Activation phase, each ship may spend a cloak token to Decloak, starting with the ship with the lowets pilot skill (using initiative to break ties).  When a ship decloaks, it must choose one of the following effects:

* Perform a barrel roll using the {straight 2} maneuver template.

* Perform a boost using the {straight 2} maneuver template.

Decloaking is not an action or a maneuver, and a ship can decloak while it has a stress token.

A ship cannot decloak if it would overlap another ship or an obstacle token, or if the maneuver template would overlap an obstacle token.

After all decloaking ships have been resolved, the Activation phase continues as normal.</Text>
	</ReferenceCard>
	<ReferenceCard>
		<Name>Stegnor's Loop</Name>
		<Text>This card explains the rules for performing a Stegnor's Loop maneuver.

The Stegnor's Loop maneuver {s-loop left or s-loop right} uses the same maneuver template as a bank maneuver (bank left or bank right).  The only difference between these maneuvers is that after executing a Stegnor's Loop , the player rotates his ship 180 degrees.  If a Stegnor's Loop maneuver causes a ship to overlap another ship, instead treat its maneuver as a bank maneuver with the same speed, color, and direction revealed on the dial.</Text>
	</ReferenceCard>
	<ReferenceCard>
		<Name>SLAM Action</Name>
		<Text>Ships with the {slam} icon in their action bar may perform a SLAM (SubLight Acceleration Motor) action.

To SLAM, choose and execute a maneuver on the ship's dial.  The chosen maneuver must be the same speed as the maneuver that ship executed this round.  Then assign that ship a weapons disabled token.

A ship with a weapons disabled token assigned to it cannot perform attacks.  Weapons disabled tokens are removed during the End phase along with focus and evade tokens.

Performing a SLAM counts as executing a maneuver.

A ship cannot perform SLAM as a free action.</Text>
	</ReferenceCard>
	<ReferenceCard>
		<Name>Tractor Beam Token</Name>
		<Text>A ship with at least one tractor beam token assigned to it follows special rules during these phases:

* Combat Phase: The agility value of that ship is reduced by 1 for each tractor beam token, to a minimum of 0.

* End Phase: Remove all tractor beam tokens from the ship.

The first time a small ship receives a tractor beam token each round, the opposing player may choose one of the following effects:

* Perform a barrel roll using the {straight 1} maneuver template.  The opposing player selects the direction of the barrel roll and the final position of the ship.

* Perform a boost using the {straight 1} maneuver template.

This is not an action or a maneuver, and can cause the ship to overlap obstacles (but not other ships).</Text>
	</ReferenceCard>
	<ReferenceCard>
		<Name>Dual Upgrade Cards</Name>
		<Text>Dual Upgrade cards are double-faced.  Because they do not have a card back, they can be identified by the symbol in the lower-left corner.

When a ship equipped with a Dual Upgrade card is placed in the play area during setup, its equipped Dual Upgrade card can be placed with either side faceup.

Dual Upgrade cards are not active until they are placed in the play area during setup.  Only the faceup side of a Dual Upgrade card is active.</Text>
	</ReferenceCard>
</ReferenceCards>