<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Upgrades Version="2.37">
	<Category id="amd" type="Astromech Droid">
		<Upgrade id="r2d2">
			<Name>R2-D2</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>After executing a green maneuver, you may recover 1 shield (up to your shield value).</Text>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="r2f2">
			<Name>R2-F2</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Action: Increase your agility value by 1 until the end of this game round.</Text>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="r5k6">
			<Name>R5-K6</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>After spending your target lock, roll 1 defense die.  On an {evade} result, immediately acquire a target lock on that same ship.  You cannot spend this target lock during this attack.</Text>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="r5astromech">
			<Name>R5 Astromech</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>During the End phase, you may choose 1 of your faceup Damage cards with the Ship trait and flip it facedown.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="r5d8">
			<Name>R5-D8</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Action: Roll 1 defense die.  On an {evade} or {focus} result, discard one of your facedown Damage cards.</Text>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="r2astromech">
			<Name>R2 Astromech</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>You may treat all 1- and 2-speed maneuvers as green maneuvers.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="r2d6">
			<Name>R2-D6</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>Your upgrade bar gains the {elite pilot talent} upgrade icon.  You cannot equip this upgrade if you already have an {elite pilot talent} upgrade icon or if your pilot skill value is "2" or lower.</Text>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<AdditionalUpgrades>
				<Upgrade>Elite Pilot Talent</Upgrade>
			</AdditionalUpgrades>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="r3a2">
			<Name>R3-A2</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When you declare the target of your attack, if the defender is inside your firing arc, you may receive 1 stress token to cause the defender to receive 1 stress token.</Text>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="r4d6">
			<Name>R4-D6</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>When you are hit by an attack and there are at least 3 uncancelled {hit} results, you may choose and cancel those results until there are 2 remaining. For each result cancelled in this way, receive 1 stress token.</Text>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="r5p9">
			<Name>R5-P9</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>At the end of the Combat phase, you may spend 1 of your focus tokens to recover 1 shield (up to your shield value).</Text>
			<Unique>true</Unique>c
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="r7t1">
			<Name>R7-T1</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Action: Choose an enemy ship at Range 1-2. If you are inside that ship's firing arc, you may acquire a target lock on that ship. Then, you may perform a free boost action.</Text>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="r7astromech">
			<Name>R7 Astromech</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>Once per round when defending, if you have a target lock on the attacker, you may spend the target lock to choose any or all attack dice.  The attacker must reroll the chosen dice.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="r5x3">
			<Name>R5-X3</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>Before you reveal your maneuver, you may discard this card to ignore obstacles until the end of the round.</Text>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="bb8">
			<Name>BB-8</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When you reveal a green maneuver, you may perform a free barrel roll action.</Text>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="targetingastromech">
			<Name>Targeting Astromech</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>After you execute a red maneuver, you may acquire a target lock.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
	</Category>
	<Category id="bomb" type="Bomb">
		<Upgrade id="proximitymines">
			<Name>Proximity Mines</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Action: Discard this card to drop 1 proximity mine token.

When a ship executes a maneuver, if its base or maneuver template overlaps this token, this token detonates.

Detonation: Proximity mines roll 3 attack dice to the ship that detonates them.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="seismiccharges">
			<Name>Seismic Charges</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When you reveal your maneuver dial, you may discard this card to drop 1 seismic charge token.

This token detonates at the end of the Activation phase.

Detonation: Seismic charges cause 1 damage to all ships within Range 1 when detonated (at the end of the Activation phase).</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="protonbombs">
			<Name>Proton Bombs</Name>
			<Cost>5</Cost>
			<Text>When you reveal your maneuver dial, you may discard this card to drop 1 proton bomb token.

This token detonates at the end of the Activation phase.

Detonation: Deal 1 faceup Damage card to each ship at Range 1 of the token. Then discard this token.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="clustermines">
			<Name>Cluster Mines</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>Action: Discard this card to drop 1 cluster mine token set.

When a ship's base or maneuver template overlaps a cluster mine token, that token detonates.

Detonation:  The ship that moved through or overlapped the token rolls 2 attack dice and suffers all damage {hit} rolled.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="connernet">
			<Name>Conner Net</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>Action: Discard this card to drop 1 Conner net token. When a ship's base or maneuver template overlaps this token, this token detonates.

Detonation: Deal one damage and two ion tokens to the affected ship. The affected ship also cannot perform actions this turn.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="ionbombs">
			<Name>Ion Bombs</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When you reveal you maneuver dial, you may discard this card to drop 1 ion bomb token.

This card detonates at the end of the Activation phase.

Detonation: Deal two ion tokens to all ships within Range 1.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
	</Category>
	<Category id="cannon" type="Cannon">
		<Upgrade id="heavylasercannon">
			<Name>Heavy Laser Cannon</Name>
			<Cost>7</Cost>
			<Text>Attack: Attack 1 ship. Immediately after rolling your attack dice, you must change all of your {crit} results to {hit} results.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>4</Dice>
			<Range>2-3</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="ioncannon">
			<Name>Ion Cannon</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Attack: Attack 1 ship.  If this attack hits, the defender suffers 1 damage and receives 1 ion token. Then cancel all dice results.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>3</Dice>
			<Range>1-3</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="autoblaster">
			<Name>Autoblaster</Name>
			<Cost>5</Cost>
			<Text>Attack: Attack 1 ship.  Your {hit} results cannot be canceled by defense dice.  The defender may cancel {crit} results before {hit} results.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>3</Dice>
			<Range>1</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="flechettecannon">
			<Name>Flechette Cannon</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>Attack: Attack 1 ship.  If this attack hits, the defender suffers 1 damage and, if the defender is not stressed, it also receives 1 stress token. Then cancel all dice results.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>3</Dice>
			<Range>1-3</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="manglercannon">
			<Name>&quot;Mangler&quot; Cannon</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>Attack: Attack 1 ship.  When attacking, you may change 1 of your {hit} results to a {crit} result.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>3</Dice>
			<Range>1-3</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="tractorbeam">
			<Name>Tractor Beam</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>Attack: Attack 1 ship.  If this attack hits, the defender receives 1 tractor beam token.  Then cancel all dice results.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>3</Dice>
			<Range>1-3</Range>
			<Preview>true</Preview>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
	</Category>
	<Category id="cargo" type="Cargo">
		<Upgrade id="backupshieldgenerator">
			<Name>Backup Shield Generator</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>At the end of each round, you may spend 1 energy to recover 1 shield (up to your shield value).</Text>
			<Limited>true</Limited>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="commsbooster">
			<Name>Comms Booster</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>Energy: Spend 1 energy to remove all stress tokens from a friendly ship at Range 1-3. Then assign 1 focus token to that ship.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="ememitter">
			<Name>EM Emitter</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>When you obstruct an attack, the defender rolls 3 additional defense dice (instead of 1).</Text>
			<Limited>true</Limited>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="enginebooster">
			<Name>Engine Booster</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Immediately before you reveal your maneuver dial, you may spend 1 energy to execute a white {straight} 1 maneuver. You cannot use this ability if you would overlap another ship.</Text>
			<Limited>true</Limited>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="expandedcargohold">
			<Name>Expanded Cargo Hold</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>Once per round, when you would be dealt a faceup Damage card, you may draw that card from either the fore or aft Damage deck.</Text>
			<Ship>gr75mediumtransport</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>GR-75</ShipRequirement>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="frequencyjammer">
			<Name>Frequency Jammer</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>When you perform a jam action, choose 1 enemy ship that does not have a stress token and is at Range 1 of the jammed ship. The chosen ship receives 1 stress token.</Text>
			<Limited>true</Limited>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="shieldprojector">
			<Name>Shield Projector</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>When an enemy ship is declaring either a small or large ship as the target of its attack, you may spend 3 energy to force that ship to target you if possible. </Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="slicertools">
			<Name>Slicer Tools</Name>
			<Cost>7</Cost>
			<Text>Action: Choose 1 or more enemy ships at Range 1-3 that have a stress token. For each ship chosen, you may spend 1 energy to cause that ship to suffer 1 damage.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="tibannagassupplies">
			<Name>Tibanna Gas Supplies</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>Energy: You may discard this card to gain 3 energy.</Text>
			<Limited>true</Limited>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="ionizationreactor">
			<Name>Ionization Reactor</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>Energy: Spend 5 energy from this card and discard this card to cause each other ship at Range 1 to suffer 1 damage and receive 1 ion token.</Text>
			<Limited>true</Limited>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="dockingclamps">
			<Name>Docking Clamps</Name>
			<Cost>0</Cost>
			<Text>You may dock up to 4 TIE Fighters, TIE Interceptors, TIE Bombers, or TIE Advanced to this ship.  All of these ships must be of the same ship type.</Text>
			<Limited>true</Limited>
			<Ship>gozanticlasscruiser</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>Gozanti-class Cruiser</ShipRequirement>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="broadcastarray">
			<Name>Broadcast Array</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>Your action bar gains the {jam} action icon.</Text>
			<Ship>gozanticlasscruiser</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>Gozanti-class Cruiser</ShipRequirement>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="clusterbombs">
			<Name>Cluster Bombs</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>After defending, you may discard this card.  If you do, each other ship at Range 1 of the defending section rolls 2 attack dice, suffering all damage {hit} and critical damage {crit} rolled.</Text>
			<Ship>gozanticlasscruiser</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>Gozanti-class Cruiser</ShipRequirement>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
	</Category>
	<Category id="crew" type="Crew">
		<Upgrade id="chewbacca">
			<Name>Chewbacca</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>When you are dealt a Damage card, you may immediately discard that card and recover 1 shield.  Then, discard this Upgrade card.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="lukeskywalker">
			<Name>Luke Skywalker</Name>
			<Cost>7</Cost>
			<Text>After you perform an attack that does not hit you may immediately perform a primary weapon attack. You may change 1 {focus} result to a {hit} result. You cannot perform another attack this round.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="niennunb">
			<Name>Nien Nunb</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>You may treat all {straight} maneuvers as green maneuvers.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="weaponsengineer">
			<Name>Weapons Engineer</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>You may maintain 2 target locks (only 1 per enemy ship).  When you acquire a target lock, you may lock onto 2 different ships.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="gunner">
			<Name>Gunner</Name>
			<Cost>5</Cost>
			<Text>After you perform an attack that does not hit you may immediately perform a primary weapon attack. You cannot perform another attack this round.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="mercenarycopilot">
			<Name>Mercenary Copilot</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When attacking at Range 3, you may change 1 of your {hit} results to a {crit} result.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="intelligenceagent">
			<Name>Intelligence Agent</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>At the start of the Activation phase, choose 1 enemy ship at Range 1-2.  You may look at that ship's chosen maneuver.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="reconspecialist">
			<Name>Recon Specialist</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>When you perform a focus action, assign 1 additional focus token to your ship.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="saboteur">
			<Name>Saboteur</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>Action: choose 1 enemy ship at Range 1 and roll 1 attack die.  On a {hit} or {crit} result, choose 1 random facedown Damage card assigned to that ship, flip it faceup, and resolve it.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="darthvader">
			<Name>Darth Vader</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>After you perform an attack against an enemy ship, you may suffer 2 damage to cause that ship to suffer 1 critical damage.</Text>
			<Faction>empire</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="rebelcaptive">
			<Name>Rebel Captive</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Once per round, the first ship that declares you as the target of an attack immediately receives 1 stress token</Text>
			<Faction>empire</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="navigator">
			<Name>Navigator</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>When you reveal a maneuver, you may rotate your dial to another maneuver with the same bearing.  You cannot rotate to a red maneuver if you have any stress tokens.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="flightinstructor">
			<Name>Flight Instructor</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>When defending, you may reroll one of your {focus} results. If the attacker's pilot skill is '2' or lower you may reroll 1 of your blank results instead.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="carlistrieekan">
			<Name>Carlist Rieekan</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>At the start of the Activation phase, you may discard this card to treat each friendly ship's pilot skill as "12" until the end of the phase.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<HugeOnly>true</HugeOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="jandodonna">
			<Name>Jan Dodonna</Name>
			<Cost>6</Cost>
			<Text>When another friendly ship at Range 1 is attacking, it may change 1 of its {hit} results to a {crit} result.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<HugeOnly>true</HugeOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="torynfarr">
			<Name>Toryn Farr</Name>
			<Cost>6</Cost>
			<Text>Action: Spend any amount of energy to choose that many enemy ships at Range 1-2. Remove all focus, evade, and blue target lock tokens from those ships.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<HugeOnly>true</HugeOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="wed15repairdroid">
			<Name>WED-15 Repair Droid</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>Action: Spend 1 energy to discard 1 of your facedown Damage cards, or spend 3 energy to discard 1 of your faceup Damage cards.</Text>
			<HugeOnly>true</HugeOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="c3po">
			<Name>C-3PO</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Once per round, before you roll 1 or more defense dice, you may guess aloud a number of {evade} results. If you roll that many {evade} results (before modifying dice), add 1 {evade} result.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="hansolo">
			<Name>Han Solo</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When attacking, if you have a target lock on the defender, you may spend that target lock to change all of your {focus} results to {hit} results.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="leiaorgana">
			<Name>Leia Organa</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>At the start of the Activation phase, you may discard this card to allow all friendly ships that reveal a red maneuver to treat that maneuver as a white maneuver until the end of the phase.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="r2d2">
			<Name>R2-D2</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>At the end of the End phase, if you have no shields, you may recover 1 shield and roll 1 attack die. On a {hit} result, randomly flip 1 of your facedown Damage cards faceup and resolve it.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="raymusantilles">
			<Name>Raymus Antilles</Name>
			<Cost>6</Cost>
			<Text>At the start of the Activation phase, choose 1 enemy ship at Range 1-3. You may look at that ship's chosen maneuver. If the maneuver is white, assign that ship 1 stress token.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<HugeOnly>true</HugeOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="targetingcoordinator">
			<Name>Targeting Coordinator</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>Energy: You may spend 1 energy to choose 1 friendly ship at Range 1-2. Acquire a target lock, then assign the blue target lock token to the chosen ship.</Text>
			<Limited>true</Limited>
			<HugeOnly>true</HugeOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="tactician">
			<Name>Tactician</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>After you perform an attack against a ship inside your firing arc at Range 2, that ship receives 1 stress token.</Text>
			<Limited>true</Limited>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="janors">
			<Name>Jan Ors</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>Once per round, when a friendly ship at Range 1-3 performs a focus action or would be assigned a focus token, you may assign that ship an evade token instead.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="kylekatarn">
			<Name>Kyle Katarn</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>After you remove a stress token from your ship, you may assign a focus token to your ship.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="landocalrissian">
			<Name>Lando Calrissian</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Action: Roll 2 defense dice. For each {focus} result, assign 1 focus token to your ship. For each {evade} result, assign 1 evade token to your ship.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="dashrendar">
			<Name>Dash Rendar</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>You may perform attacks while overlapping an obstacle.  Your attacks cannot be obstructed.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="leebo">
			<Name>&quot;Leebo&quot;</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>Action: Perform a free boost action. Then receive 1 ion token.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="fleetofficer">
			<Name>Fleet Officer</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Action: Choose up to 2 friendly ships at Range 1-2 and assign 1 focus token to each of those ships. Then receive 1 stress token.</Text>
			<Faction>empire</Faction>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="marajade">
			<Name>Mara Jade</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>At the end of the Combat phase, each enemy ship at Range 1 that does not have a stress token receives 1 stress token.</Text>
			<Faction>empire</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="moffjerjerrod">
			<Name>Moff Jerjerrod</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When you are dealt a faceup Damage card, you may discard this Upgrade card or another {crew} Upgrade card to flip that Damage card facedown (without resolving its effect).</Text>
			<Faction>empire</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="ysanneisard">
			<Name>Ysanne Isard</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>At the start of the Combat phase, if you have no shields and at least 1 Damage card assigned to your ship, you may perform a free evade action.</Text>
			<Faction>empire</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="greedo">
			<Name>Greedo</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>The first time you attack each round and the first time you defend each round, the first Damage card dealt is dealt faceup.</Text>
			<Faction>scum</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="k4securitydroid">
			<Name>K4 Security Droid</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>After executing a green maneuver, you may acquire a target lock.</Text>
			<Faction>scum</Faction>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="outlawtech">
			<Name>Outlaw Tech</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>After you execute a red maneuver, you may assign 1 focus token to your ship.</Text>
			<Faction>scum</Faction>
			<Limited>true</Limited>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="bombardier">
			<Name>Bombardier</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>When dropping a bomb, you may use the [{straight} 2] template instead of the [{straight} 1] template.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="bossk">
			<Name>Bossk</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>After you perform an attack that does not hit, if you are not stressed, you must receive 1 stress token.  Then assign 1 focus token to your ship and acquire a target lock on the defender.</Text>
			<Faction>scum</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="emperorpalpatine">
			<Name>Emperor Palpatine</Name>
			<Cost>8</Cost>
			<Text>Once per round, you may change a friendly ship's die result to any other die result.  That die result cannot be modified again.</Text>
			<Faction>empire</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<ExtraSlots>
				<Upgrade>Crew</Upgrade>
			</ExtraSlots>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="admiralozzel">
			<Name>Admiral Ozzel</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>If you overlap an obstacle during the Activation Phase, do not suffer 1 faceup damage card. Instead, roll 1 attack die. On a {hit} or {crit} result, suffer 1 damage.</Text>
			<Faction>empire</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<HugeOnly>true</HugeOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="captainneeda">
			<Name>Captain Needa</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>Energy: You may remove up to 3 shields from your ship.  For each shield removed, gain 1 energy.</Text>
			<Faction>empire</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<HugeOnly>true</HugeOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="grandmofftarkin">
			<Name>Grand Moff Tarkin</Name>
			<Cost>6</Cost>
			<Text>At the start of the Combat Phase, you may choose another ship at Range 1-4. Either remove 1 focus token from the chosen ship or assign 1 focus token to that ship.</Text>
			<Faction>empire</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<HugeOnly>true</HugeOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="shieldtechnician">
			<Name>Shield Technician</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>When you perform a recover action, instead of spending all of your energy, you can choose any amount of energy to spend.</Text>
			<HugeOnly>true</HugeOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="agentkallus">
			<Name>Agent Kallus</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>At the start of the first round, choose 1 enemy small or large ship.  When attacking or defending against that ship, you may change one of your {focus} results to a {hit} or {evade} result.</Text>
			<Faction>empire</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="rearadmiralchiraneau">
			<Name>Rear Admiral Chiraneau</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Action: Execute a white 1 {straight} maneuver.</Text>
			<Faction>empire</Faction>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<HugeOnly>true</HugeOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="constructiondroid">
			<Name>Construction Droid</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>When you perform a recover action, you may spend 1 energy to discard 1 facedown damage card.</Text>
			<Limited>true</Limited>
			<HugeOnly>true</HugeOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="kananjarrus">
			<Name>Kanan Jarrus</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Once per round, after a friendly ship at Range 1-2 executes a white maneuver, you may remove 1 stress token from that ship.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Preview>true</Preview>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="zeborrelios">
			<Name>&quot;Zeb&quot; Orrelios</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>Enemy ships inside your firing arc that you are touching are not considered to be touching you when either you or they activate during the Combat phase.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Preview>true</Preview>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="herasyndulla">
			<Name>Hera Syndulla</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>You can reveal and execute red maneuvers even while you are stressed.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Preview>true</Preview>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="ezrabridger">
			<Name>Ezra Bridger</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>When attacking, if you are stressed, you may change 1 of your {focus} results to a {crit} result.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Preview>true</Preview>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="sabinewren">
			<Name>Sabine Wren</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>Your upgrade bar gains the {bomb} upgrade icon.  Once per round, before a friendly bomb token is removed, choose 1 enemy ship at Range 1 of that token.  That ship suffers 1 damage.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Preview>true</Preview>
			<AdditionalUpgrades>
				<Upgrade>Bomb</Upgrade>
			</AdditionalUpgrades>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="chopper">
			<Name>&quot;Chopper&quot;</Name>
			<Cost>0</Cost>
			<Text>You may perform actions even while you are stressed.

After you perform an action while you are stressed.  Suffer 1 damage.</Text>
			<Faction>rebels</Faction>
			<Preview>true</Preview>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
	</Category>
	<Category id="ept" type="Elite Pilot Talent">
		<Upgrade id="determination">
			<Name>Determination</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>When you are dealth a faceup Damage card with the Pilot trait, discard it immediately without resolving its effect.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="marksmanship">
			<Name>Marksmanship</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Action: When attacking this round, you may change 1 of your {focus} results to a {crit} result and all your other {focus} results to {hit} results.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="experthandling">
			<Name>Expert Handling</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>Action: Perform a free barrel roll action.  If you do not have the {barrel roll} action icon, receive 1 stress token.  You may then remove 1 enemy target lock from your ship.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="swarmtactics">
			<Name>Swarm Tactics</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>At the start of the Combat phase, choose 1 friendly ship at Range 1.  Until the end of this phase, treat the chosen ship as if its pilot skill were equal to your pilot skill.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="squadleader">
			<Name>Squad Leader</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>Action: Choose 1 ship at Range 1-2 that has a lower pilot skill than you.  The chosen ship may immediately perform 1 free action.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="drawtheirfire">
			<Name>Draw Their Fire</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>When a friendly ship at Range 1 is hit by an attack, you may suffer one of the uncancelled {crit} results instead of the target ship.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="elusiveness">
			<Name>Elusiveness</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When defending, you may receive 1 stress token to choose 1 attack die.  The attacker must reroll that die.  If you have at least 1 stress token, you cannot use this ability.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="veteraninstincts">
			<Name>Veteran Instincts</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<PilotSkill>2</PilotSkill>
			<Text>Increase your pilot skill value by 2.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="expose">
			<Name>Expose</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>Action: Until the end of the round, increase your primary weapon value by 1 and decrease your agility value by 1.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="deadeye">
			<Name>Deadeye</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>You may treat the 'Attack (target lock):' header as 'Attack (focus):'.  When an attack instructs you to spend a target lock, you may spend a focus token instead.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="pushthelimit">
			<Name>Push The Limit</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Once per round, after you perform an action, you may perform 1 free action shown in your action bar.  Then receive 1 stress token.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="daredevil">
			<Name>Daredevil</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Action: Execute a white {left turn 1} or {right turn 1} maneuver.  Then receive 1 stress token.  Then, if you do not have the {boost} action icon, roll 2 attack dice.  Suffer any damage {hit} and critical damage {crit} rolled.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="adrenalinerush">
			<Name>Adrenaline Rush</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>When you reveal a red maneuver, you may discard this card to treat that maneuver as a white maneuver until the end of the Activation phase.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="opportunist">
			<Name>Opportunist</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>When attacking, if the defender does not have any focus or evade tokens, you may receive 1 stress token to roll 1 additional attack die.  You cannot use this ability if you have any stress tokens.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="wingman">
			<Name>Wingman</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>At the start of the Combat phase, remove 1 stress token from another friendly ship at Range 1.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="decoy">
			<Name>Decoy</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>At the start of the combat phase, you may choose 1 friendly ship at Range 1-2.  Exchange your pilot skill with that ship's pilot skill until the end of the phase. </Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="predator">
			<Name>Predator</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>When attacking, you may reroll 1 attack die.  If the defender's pilot skill value is "2" or lower, you may instead reroll up to 2 attack dice.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="outmaneuver">
			<Name>Outmaneuver</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>When attacking a ship inside your firing arc, if you are not inside that ship's firing arc, reduce its agility value by 1 (to a minimum of 0).</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="lonewolf">
			<Name>Lone Wolf</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When attacking or defending, if there are no other friendly ships at Range 1-2, you may reroll 1 of your blank results.</Text>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="stayontarget">
			<Name>Stay On Target</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When you reveal a maneuver, you may rotate your dial to another maneuver with the same speed.  Treat that maneuver as a red maneuver.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="intimidation">
			<Name>Intimidation</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When you are touching an enemy ship, reduce that ship's agility value by 1.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="ruthlessness">
			<Name>Ruthlessness</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Faction>empire</Faction>
			<Text>After you perform an attack that hits, you must choose 1 other ship at Range 1 of the defender (other than yourself).  That ship suffers 1 damage.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="bodyguard">
			<Name>Bodyguard</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Faction>scum</Faction>
			<Text>At the start of the Combat phase, you may spend a focus token to choose a friendly ship at Range 1 with a higher pilot skill than you. Increase its agility value by 1 until the end of the round.</Text>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="calculation">
			<Name>Calculation</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>When attacking, you may spend a focus token to change 1 of your {focus} results to a {crit} result.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="lightningreflexes">
			<Name>Lightning Reflexes</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>After you execute a white or green maneuver on your dial, you may discard this card to rotate your ship 180 degrees.  Then receive 1 stress token after the &quot;Check Pilot Stress&quot; step.</Text>
			<SmallOnly>true</SmallOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="crackshot">
			<Name>Crack Shot</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>When attacking a ship inside your firing arc, you may discard this card to cancel 1 of the defender's {evade} results.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="wired">
			<Name>Wired</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>When attacking or defending, if you are stressed, you may reroll 1 or more of your {focus} results.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="coolhand">
			<Name>Cool Hand</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>When you receive a stress token, you may discard this card to assign 1 focus or evade token to your ship.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="juke">
			<Name>Juke</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When attacking, if you have an evade token, you may change 1 of the defender’s {evade} results to a {focus} result.</Text>
			<SmallOnly>true</SmallOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
	</Category>
	<Category id="hardpoint" type="Hardpoint">
		<Upgrade id="quadlasercannons">
			<Name>Quad Laser Cannons</Name>
			<Cost>6</Cost>
			<Text>Attack (energy): Spend 1 energy from this card to perform this attack. If this attack does not hit, you may immediately spend 1 energy from this card to perform this attack again.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Energy>2</Energy>
			<Dice>3</Dice>
			<Range>1-2</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="singleturbolasers">
			<Name>Single Turbolasers</Name>
			<Cost>8</Cost>
			<Text>Attack (energy): Spend 2 energy from this card to perform this attack. The defender doubles his agility value against this attack. You may change 1 of your {focus} results to a {hit} result.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Energy>2</Energy>
			<Dice>4</Dice>
			<Range>3-5</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="ioncannonbattery">
			<Name>Ion Cannon Battery</Name>
			<Cost>6</Cost>
			<Text>Attack (Energy): Spend 2 energy from this card to perform this attack. If this attack hits, the defender suffers 1 critical damage and receives 1 ion token. Then cancel all dice results.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Energy>2</Energy>
			<Dice>4</Dice>
			<Range>2-4</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="duallaserturret">
			<Name>Dual Laser Turret</Name>
			<Cost>5</Cost>
			<Text>Attack (Energy): Spend 1 energy from this card to perform this attack against 1 ship (even a ship outside of your firing arc).</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Energy>1</Energy>
			<Dice>3</Dice>
			<Range>1-3</Range>
			<Ship>gozanticlasscruiser</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>Gozanti-class Cruiser</ShipRequirement>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
	</Category>
	<Category id="illicit" type="Illicit">
		<Upgrade id="hotshotblaster">
			<Name>&quot;Hot Shot&quot; Blaster</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Attack: Discard this card to attack 1 ship (even a ship outside your firing arc).</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>3</Dice>
			<Range>1-2</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="inertialdampeners">
			<Name>Inertial Dampeners</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>When you reveal your maneuver, you may discard this card to instead perform a white {stationary} 0 maneuver. Then receive 1 stress token.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="feedbackarray">
			<Name>Feedback Array</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>During the Combat phase, instead of performing any attacks, you may receive 1 ion token and suffer 1 damage to choose 1 enemy ship at Range 1. That ship suffers 1 damage.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="deadmansswitch">
			<Name>Dead Man's Switch</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When you are destroyed, each ship at Range 1 suffers one damage.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="glitterstim">
			<Name>Glitterstim</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>At the start of the Combat phase, you may discard this card and receive 1 stress token. If you do, until the end of the round, when attacking or defending, you may change all of your {focus} results to {hit} or {evade} results.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="cloakingdevice">
			<Name>Cloaking Device</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>Action: Perform a free cloak action.  At the end of each round, if you are cloaked, roll 1 attack die.  On a {focus} result, discard this card, then decloak or discard your cloak token.</Text>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Preview>true</Preview>
			<SmallOnly>true</SmallOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
	</Category>
	<Category id="missile" type="Missile">
		<Upgrade id="clustermissiles">
			<Name>Cluster Missiles</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>Attack (target lock): Spend your target lock and discard this card to perform this attack twice.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>3</Dice>
			<Range>1-2</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="concussionmissiles">
			<Name>Concussion Missiles</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>Attack (target lock): Spend your target lock and discard this card to peform this attack.  You may change 1 of your blank results to a {hit} result.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>4</Dice>
			<Range>2-3</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="assaultmissiles">
			<Name>Assault Missiles</Name>
			<Cost>5</Cost>
			<Text>Attack (target lock): Spend your target lock and discard this card to perform this attack.  If this attack hits, each other ship at Range 1 of the defender suffers 1 damage.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>4</Dice>
			<Range>2-3</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="homingmissiles">
			<Name>Homing Missiles</Name>
			<Cost>5</Cost>
			<Text>Attack (target lock): Discard this card to perform this attack.  The defender cannot spend evade tokens during this attack.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>4</Dice>
			<Range>2-3</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="ionpulsemissiles">
			<Name>Ion Pulse Missiles</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Attack (target lock): Discard this card to peform this attack.  If this attack hits, the defender suffers 1 damage and recieves 2 ion tokens. Then cancel all dice results.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>3</Dice>
			<Range>2-3</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="chardaanrefit">
			<Name>Chardaan Refit</Name>
			<Cost>-2</Cost>
			<Text>This card has a negative squad point cost.</Text>
			<Ship>awing</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>A-Wing</ShipRequirement>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="protonrockets">
			<Name>Proton Rockets</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Attack (Focus): Discard this card to perform this attack.  You may roll additional attack dice equal to your agility value, to a maximum of 3 additional dice.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>2</Dice>
			<Range>1</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="advancedhomingmissiles">
			<Name>Adv. Homing Missiles</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Attack (target lock): Discard this card to perform this attack.  If this attack hits, deal 1 faceup Damage card to the defender.  Then cancel all dice results.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>3</Dice>
			<Range>2</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="xx23sthreadtracers">
			<Name>XX-23 S-Thread Tracers</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>Attack (Focus): Discard this card to perform this attack.  If this attack hits, each friendly ship at range 1-2 of you may acquire a target lock on the defender.  Then cancel all dice results.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>3</Dice>
			<Range>1-3</Range>
			<Preview>true</Preview>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
	</Category>
	<Category id="mod" type="Modification">
		<Upgrade id="engineupgrade">
			<Name>Engine Upgrade</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>Your action bar gains the {boost} action icon.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="shieldupgrade">
			<Name>Shield Upgrade</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>Increase your shield value by 1.</Text>
			<Shields>1</Shields>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="stealthdevice">
			<Name>Stealth Device</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Increase your agility value by 1. If you are hit by an attack, discard this card.</Text>
			<Agility>1</Agility>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="antipursuitlasers">
			<Name>Anti-Pursuit Lasers</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>After an enemy ship executes a maneuver that causes it to overlap your ship, roll 1 attack die.  On a {hit} or {crit} result, the enemy ship suffers 1 damage.</Text>
			<LargeOnly>true</LargeOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="targetingcomputer">
			<Name>Targeting Computer</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>Your action bar gains the {target lock} action icon.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="hullupgrade">
			<Name>Hull Upgrade</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Increase your hull value by 1.</Text>
			<Hull>1</Hull>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="combatretrofit">
			<Name>Combat Retrofit</Name>
			<Cost>10</Cost>
			<Text>Increase your hull value by 2 and your shield value by 1.</Text>
			<Ship>gr75mediumtransport</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>GR-75</ShipRequirement>
			<HugeOnly>true</HugeOnly>
			<Hull>2</Hull>
			<Shields>1</Shields>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="munitionsfailsafe">
			<Name>Munitions Failsafe</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>When attacking with a secondary weapon that instructs you to discard it to perform the attack, do not discard it unless the attack hits.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="advancedcloakingdevice">
			<Name>Advanced Cloaking Device</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>After you perform an attack, you may perform a free cloak action. </Text>
			<Ship>tiephantom</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>TIE Phantom</ShipRequirement>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="stygiumparticleaccelerator">
			<Name>Stygium Particle Accelerator</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When you either decloak or perform a cloak action, you may perform a free evade action.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="bwinge2">
			<Name>B-Wing/E2</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>Your upgrade bar gains the {crew} upgrade icon.</Text>
			<Ship>bwing</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>B-Wing</ShipRequirement>
			<AdditionalUpgrades>
				<Upgrade>Crew</Upgrade>
			</AdditionalUpgrades>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="countermeasures">
			<Name>Countermeasures</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>At the start of the Combat phase, you may discard this card to increase your agility value by 1 until the end of the round. Then you may remove 1 enemy target lock from your ship.</Text>
			<LargeOnly>true</LargeOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="experimentalinterface">
			<Name>Experimental Interface</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Once per round, after you perform an action, you may perform 1 free action from an equipped Upgrade card with the "Action:" header. Then receive 1 stress token.</Text>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="tacticaljammers">
			<Name>Tactical Jammers</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>Your ship can obstruct enemy attacks.</Text>
			<LargeOnly>true</LargeOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="autothrusters">
			<Name>Autothrusters</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When defending, if you are beyond Range 2 or outside the attacker's firing arc, you may change 1 of your blank results to an {evade} result. You can equip this card only if you have the {boost} action icon.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="ionprojector">
			<Name>Ion Projector</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>After an enemy ship executes a maneuver that causes it to overlap your ship, roll 1 attack die.  On a {hit} or {crit} result, the enemy ship receives one ion token.</Text>
			<LargeOnly>true</LargeOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="maneuveringfins">
			<Name>Maneuvering Fins</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>When you reveal a turn maneuver ({left turn} or {right turn}) you may rotate your dial to the corresponding bank maneuver ({left bank} or {right bank}) of the same speed.</Text>
			<Ship>yv666</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>YV-666</ShipRequirement>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="advancedslam">
			<Name>Advanced SLAM</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>After performing a SLAM action, if you did not overlap an obstacle or another ship, you may perform a free action.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="twinionenginemkii">
			<Name>Twin Ion Engine Mk. II</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>You may treat all bank maneuvers ({bank left} or {bank right}) as green maneuvers.</Text>
			<ShipRequirement>TIE</ShipRequirement>
			<TIEOnly>true</TIEOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="integratedastromech">
			<Name>Integrated Astromech</Name>
			<Cost>0</Cost>
			<Text>When you are dealt a Damage card you may discard one of your {astromech droid} Upgrade cards to discard that Damage card (without resolving its effect).</Text>
			<Ship>xwing</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>X-Wing</ShipRequirement>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="automatedprotocols">
			<Name>Automated Protocols</Name>
			<Cost>5</Cost>
			<Text>Once per round, after you perform an action that is not a recover or reinforce action, you may spend 1 energy to perform a free recover or reinforce action.</Text>
			<HugeOnly>true</HugeOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="optimizedgenerators">
			<Name>Optimized Generators</Name>
			<Cost>5</Cost>
			<Text>Once per round, when you assign energy to an equipped Upgrade card, gain 2 energy.</Text>
			<HugeOnly>true</HugeOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="ordnancetubes">
			<Name>Ordnance Tubes</Name>
			<Cost>5</Cost>
			<Text>You may treat each of your {hardpoint} upgrade icons as a {torpedo} or {missile} upgrade icon.

When you are instructed to discard a {torpedo} or {missile} upgrade card, do not discard it.</Text>
			<HugeOnly>true</HugeOnly>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="longrangescanners">
			<Name>Long-Range Scanners</Name>
			<Cost>0</Cost>
			<Text>You can acquire target locks on ships at Range 3 and beyond.  You cannot acquire target locks on ships at range 1-2.  You can equip this card only if you have {torpedo} and {missile} in your upgrade bar.</Text>
			<RequiredSlots>
				<Upgrade>Torpedo</Upgrade>
				<Upgrade>Missile</Upgrade>
			</RequiredSlots>
			<Preview>true</Preview>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="guidancechips">
			<Name>Guidance Chips</Name>
			<Cost>0</Cost>
			<Text>Once per round, when attacking with a {torpedo} or {missile} secondary weapon, you may change 1 die result to a {hit} result (or a {crit} result if your primary weapon value is '3' or higher).</Text>
			<Preview>true</Preview>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
	</Category>
	<Category id="samd" type="Salvaged Astromech">
		<Upgrade id="r4agromech">
			<Name>R4 Agromech</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When attacking, after you spend a focus token, you may acquire a target lock on the defender.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="unhingedastromech">
			<Name>Unhinged Astromech</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>You may treat all 3-speed maneuvers as green maneuvers.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="genius">
			<Name>&quot;Genius&quot;</Name>
			<Cost>0</Cost>
			<Text>If you are equipped with a bomb that can be dropped before you reveal your maneuver, you may drop the bomb after you execute your maneuver instead.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="r4b11">
			<Name>R4-B11</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>When attacking, if you have a target lock on the defender, you may spend the target lock to choose any or all defense dice. The defender must reroll the chosen dice.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="salvagedastromech">
			<Name>Salvaged Astromech</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When you are dealt a Damage card with the Ship trait, you may immediately discard that card (before resolving its effect). Then discard this Upgrade card.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
	</Category>
	<Category id="system" type="System Upgrade">
		<Upgrade id="advancedsensors">
			<Name>Advanced Sensors</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Immediately before you reveal your maneuver, you may perform 1 free action.  If you use this ability, you must skip your "Perform action" step during this round.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="sensorjammer">
			<Name>Sensor Jammer</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>When defending, you may change 1 of the attacker's {hit} results to a {focus} result.  The attacker cannot reroll the die with the changed result.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="firecontrolsystem">
			<Name>Fire Control System</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>After you perform an attack, you may acquire a target lock on the defender.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="enhancedscopes">
			<Name>Enhanced Scopes</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>During the Activation phase, treat your pilot skill value as 0.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="accuraccorrector">
			<Name>Accuracy Corrector</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>When attacking, you may cancel all of your dice results. Then, you may add 2 {hit} results to your roll. Your dice cannot be modified again during this attack.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="advancedtargetingcomputer">
			<Name>Advanced Targeting Computer</Name>
			<Cost>5</Cost>
			<Text>When attacking with your primary weapon, if you have a target lock on the defender, you may add 1 {crit} result to your roll. If you do, you cannot spend target locks during this attack.</Text>
			<Ship>tieadvanced</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>TIE Advanced</ShipRequirement>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="reinforceddeflectors">
			<Name>Reinforced Deflectors</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>After you suffer 3 or more damage from an attack, recover 1 shield (up to your shield value).</Text>
			<LargeOnly>true</LargeOnly>
			<Preview>true</Preview>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
	</Category>
	<Category id="team" type="Team">
		<Upgrade id="gunneryteam">
			<Name>Gunnery Team</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>Once per round, when attacking with a secondary weapon, you may spend 1 energy to change 1 of your blank results to a {hit} result.</Text>
			<Limited>true</Limited>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="engineeringteam">
			<Name>Engineering Team</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>During the Activation phase, when you reveal a {straight} maneuver, gain 1 additional energy during the "Gain Energy" step.</Text>
			<Limited>true</Limited>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="sensorteam">
			<Name>Sensor Team</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>When acquiring a target lock, you may lock onto an enemy ship at Range 1-5 (instead of Range 1-3).</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="ordnanceexperts">
			<Name>Ordnance Experts</Name>
			<Cost>5</Cost>
			<Text>Once per round when a Friendly ship at Range 1-3 performs an attack with a {missile} or {torpedo} secondary weapon, it may change 1 of its blank results to a {hit} result.</Text>
			<Limited>true</Limited>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
	</Category>
	<Category id="title" type="Title">
		<Upgrade id="milleniumfalcon">
			<Name>Millenium Falcon</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>Your action bar gains the Evade action icon.</Text>
			<Ship>yt1300</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>YT-1300</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>True</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="slavei">
			<Name>Slave I</Name>
			<Cost>0</Cost>
			<Text>Your upgrade bar gains the {torpedo} upgrade icon.</Text>
			<Ship>firespray31</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>Firespray-31</ShipRequirement>
			<AdditionalUpgrades>
				<Upgrade>Torpedo</Upgrade>
			</AdditionalUpgrades>
			<Unique>True</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="moldycrow">
			<Name>Moldy Crow</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>During the End phase, do not remove unused focus tokens from your ship.</Text>
			<Ship>hwk290</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>HWK-290</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>True</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="st321">
			<Name>ST-321</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>When acquiring a target lock, you may lock onto any enemy ship in the play area.</Text>
			<Ship>lambdaclassshuttle</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>Lambda-class Shuttle</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>True</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="royalguardtie">
			<Name>Royal Guard TIE</Name>
			<Cost>0</Cost>
			<Text>You may equip up to 2 different Modifications. You cannot equip this card if your Pilot skill is 4 or less.</Text>
			<Ship>tieinterceptor</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>TIE Interceptor</ShipRequirement>
			<AdditionalUpgrades>
				<Upgrade>Modification</Upgrade>
			</AdditionalUpgrades>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="brighthope">
			<Name>Bright Hope</Name>
			<Cost>5</Cost>
			<Text>+2 Energy

A reinforce token assigned to your fore section adds 2 {evade} results (instead of 1).</Text>
			<Ship>gr75mediumtransport</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>GR-75</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>True</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="dutyfree">
			<Name>Dutyfree</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When performing a jam action, you may choose an enemy ship at Range 1-3 (instead of at Range 1-2).</Text>
			<Ship>gr75mediumtransport</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>GR-75</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>True</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="quantumstorm">
			<Name>Quantum Storm</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>+1 Energy

At the start of the End phase, if you have 1 or fewer energy tokens, gain 1 energy token.</Text>
			<Energy>1</Energy>
			<Ship>gr75mediumtransport</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>GR-75</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>True</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="dodonnaspride">
			<Name>Dodonna's Pride</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>When you perform a coordinate action, you may choose 2 friendly ships (instead of 1). Those ships may each perform 1 free action.</Text>
			<Ship>cr90f</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>CR90 Fore</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>True</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="jainaslight">
			<Name>Jaina's Light</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When defending, once per attack, if you are dealt a faceup Damage card, you may discard it and draw another faceup Damage card.</Text>
			<Ship>cr90f</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>CR90 Fore</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>True</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="tantiveiv">
			<Name>Tantive IV</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>Your fore section upgrade bar gains 1 additional {crew} and 1 additional {team} upgrade icon.</Text>
			<Ship>cr90f</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>CR90 Fore</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>True</Unique>
			<AdditionalUpgrades>
				<Upgrade>Crew</Upgrade>
				<Upgrade>Team</Upgrade>
			</AdditionalUpgrades>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="awingtestpilot">
			<Name>A-Wing Test Pilot</Name>
			<Cost>0</Cost>
			<Text>Your upgrade bar gains 1 Elite Upgrade icon. You cannot equip 2 of the same Elite Upgrade cards. You cannot equip this card if your pilot skill value is "1" or lower.</Text>
			<Ship>awing</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>A-Wing</ShipRequirement>
			<AdditionalUpgrades>
				<Upgrade>Elite Pilot Talent</Upgrade>
			</AdditionalUpgrades>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="outrider">
			<Name>Outrider</Name>
			<Cost>5</Cost>
			<Text>While you have a {cannon} Upgrade card equipped, you cannot perform primary weapon attacks and you may perform {cannon} secondary weapons attacks against ships outside your firing arc.</Text>
			<Ship>yt2400</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>YT-2400</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>True</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="dauntless">
			<Name>Dauntless</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>After you execute a maneuver that causes you to overlap another ship, you may perform one free action. Then receive 1 stress token.</Text>
			<Ship>vt49decimator</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>VT-49 Decimator</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>True</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="virago">
			<Name>Virago</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>Your upgrade bar gains the {system} and {illicit} upgrade icons.  You cannot equip this card if your pilot skill value is "3" or lower.</Text>
			<Ship>starviper</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>StarViper</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>True</Unique>
			<AdditionalUpgrades>
				<Upgrade>System Upgrade</Upgrade>
				<Upgrade>Illicit</Upgrade>
			</AdditionalUpgrades>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="heavyscykinterceptor">
			<Name>&quot;Heavy Scyk&quot; Interceptor</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>Your upgrade bar gains the {cannon}, {torpedo} or {missile} upgrade icon.</Text>
			<Ship>m3ainterceptor</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>M3-A Interceptor</ShipRequirement>
			<UpgradeOptions>
				<Upgrade>Cannon</Upgrade>
				<Upgrade>Torpedo</Upgrade>
				<Upgrade>Missile</Upgrade>
			</UpgradeOptions>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="ig2000">
			<Name>IG-2000</Name>
			<Cost>0</Cost>
			<Text>You have the pilot ability of each other friendly ship with the IG-2000 Upgrade card (in addition to your own pilot ability).</Text>
			<Ship>aggressor</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>Aggressor</ShipRequirement>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="btla4ywing">
			<Name>BTL-A4 Y-wing</Name>
			<Cost>0</Cost>
			<Text>You cannot attack ships outside your firing arc. After you perform a primary weapon attack, you may immediately perform an attack with a {turret} secondary weapon.</Text>
			<Ship>ywing</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>Y-Wing</ShipRequirement>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="andrasta">
			<Name>Andrasta</Name>
			<Cost>0</Cost>
			<Text>Your upgrade bar gains two additional {bomb} upgrade icons.</Text>
			<Ship>firespray31</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>Firespray-31</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>True</Unique>
			<AdditionalUpgrades>
				<Upgrade>Bomb</Upgrade>
				<Upgrade>Bomb</Upgrade>
			</AdditionalUpgrades>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="tiex1">
			<Name>TIE/x1</Name>
			<Cost>0</Cost>
			<Text>Your upgrade bar gains the {system} upgrade icon.  If you equip a {system} upgrade, its squad point cost is reduced by 4 (to a minimum of 0).</Text>
			<Ship>tieadvanced</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>TIE Advanced</ShipRequirement>
			<AdditionalUpgrades>
				<Upgrade>System Upgrade</Upgrade>
			</AdditionalUpgrades>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="houndstooth">
			<Name>Hound's Tooth</Name>
			<Cost>6</Cost>
			<Text>After you are destroyed, before you are removed from the play area, you may deploy the Nashtah Pup Pilot.  It cannot attack this round.</Text>
			<Ship>yv666</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>YV-666</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>True</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="assailer">
			<Name>Assailer</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When defending, if the target section has a reinforce token you may change 1 {focus} result to an {evade} result.</Text>
			<Ship>raidera</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>Raider-class Corv. Aft</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>True</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="impetuous">
			<Name>Impetuous</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>After you perform an attack that destroys an enemy ship you may acquire a target lock.</Text>
			<Ship>raidera</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>Raider-class Corv. Aft</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>True</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="instigator">
			<Name>Instigator</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>After you perform a recover action, recover 1 additional shield.</Text>
			<Ship>raidera</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>Raider-class Corv. Aft</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>True</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="requiem">
			<Name>Requiem</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>When you deploy a ship, treat it's pilot skill value as &quot;8&quot; until the end of the round.</Text>
			<Ship>gozanticlasscruiser</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>Gozanti-class Cruiser</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>True</Unique>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="suppressor">
			<Name>Suppressor</Name>
			<Cost>6</Cost>
			<Text>Once per round, after you acquire a target lock on an enemy ship, you may remove 1 focus, evade or blue target lock token from that ship.</Text>
			<Ship>gozanticlasscruiser</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>Gozanti-class Cruiser</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>True</Unique>
			<Energy>2</Energy>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="vector">
			<Name>Vector</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>After you execute a maneuver, you may deploy up to 4 undocked ships (instead of 2).</Text>
			<Ship>gozanticlasscruiser</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>Gozanti-class Cruiser</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>True</Unique>
			<Energy>1</Energy>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="ghost">
			<Name>Ghost</Name>
			<Cost>0</Cost>
			<Text>Equip the Phantom title card to a friendly Attack Shuttle and dock it to this ship.  After you execute a maneuver you may deploy it from your rear guides.</Text>
			<Ship>vcx100</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>VCX-100</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Preview>true</Preview>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="phantom">
			<Name>Phantom</Name>
			<Cost>0</Cost>
			<Text>While you are docked, the Ghost can perform primary weapon attacks from its special firing arc and at the end of the Combat Phase, it may perform an additional attack with an equipped {turret}.  If it performs this attack, it cannot attack again this round.</Text>
			<Ship>attackshuttle</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>Attack Shuttle</ShipRequirement>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Preview>true</Preview>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="misthunter">
			<Name>Mist Hunter</Name>
			<Cost>0</Cost>
			<Text>Your action bar gains the {barrel roll} action icon.  You must equip 1 "Tractor Beam" Upgrade Card (paying the squad cost as normal).</Text>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Ship>g1astarfighter</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>G-1A Starfighter</ShipRequirement>
			<Preview>true</Preview>
			<AdditionalUpgrades>
				<Upgrade>Cannon</Upgrade>
			</AdditionalUpgrades>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="punishingone">
			<Name>Punishing One</Name>
			<Cost>12</Cost>
			<Text>Increase your primary weapon value by 1.</Text>
			<Unique>true</Unique>
			<Ship>jumpmaster5000</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>JumpMaster 5000</ShipRequirement>
			<Preview>true</Preview>
			<Attack>1</Attack>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="tiev1">
			<Name>TIE/v1</Name>
			<Cost>1</Cost>
			<Text>After you acquire a target lock, you may perform a free evade action.</Text>
			<Ship>tieadvancedprototype</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>TIE Adv. Prototype</ShipRequirement>
			<Preview>true</Preview>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="tiex7">
			<Name>TIE/x7</Name>
			<Cost>-2</Cost>
			<Text>Your upgrade bar loses the {cannon} and {missile} upgrade icons.  

After executing a 3-, 4-, or 5-speed maneuver, you may assign 1 evade token to your ship.</Text>
			<Ship>tiedefender</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>TIE Defender</ShipRequirement>
			<Preview>true</Preview>
			<RemovedUpgrades>
				<Upgrade>Cannon</Upgrade>
				<Upgrade>Missile</Upgrade>
			</RemovedUpgrades>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="tied">
			<Name>TIE/D</Name>
			<Cost>0</Cost>
			<Text>Once per round, after you perform an attack with a {cannon} secondary weapon that costs 3 or fewer squad points, you may perform a primary weapon attack.</Text>
			<Ship>tiedefender</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>TIE Defender</ShipRequirement>
			<Preview>true</Preview>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="tieshuttle">
			<Name>TIE Shuttle</Name>
			<Cost>0</Cost>
			<Text>Your upgrade bar loses all {torpedo}, {missile}, and {bomb} upgrade icons and gains 2 {crew} upgrade icons.  You cannot equip a {crew} Upgrade card that costs more than 4 squad points.</Text>
			<Ship>tiebomber</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>TIE Bomber</ShipRequirement>
			<Preview>true</Preview>
			<RemovedUpgrades>
				<Upgrade>Missile</Upgrade>
				<Upgrade>Missile</Upgrade>
				<Upgrade>Bomb</Upgrade>
				<Upgrade>Torpedo</Upgrade>
				<Upgrade>Torpedo</Upgrade>
			</RemovedUpgrades>
			<AdditionalUpgrades>
				<Upgrade>Crew</Upgrade>
				<Upgrade>Crew</Upgrade>
			</AdditionalUpgrades>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
	</Category>
	<Category id="torpedo" type="Torpedo">
		<Upgrade id="protontorpedoes">
			<Name>Proton Torpedoes</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>Attack (target lock): Spend your target lock and discard this card to perform this attack.  You may change 1 of your {focus} results to a {crit} result.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>4</Dice>
			<Range>2-3</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="advancedprotontorpedoes">
			<Name>Advanced Proton Torpedoes</Name>
			<Cost>6</Cost>
			<Text>Attack (target lock): Spend your target lock and discard this card to perform this attack. You may change up to 3 of your blank results to {focus} results.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>5</Dice>
			<Range>1</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="flechettetorpedoes">
			<Name>Flechette Torpedoes</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>Attack (target lock): Discard this card and spend your target lock to perform this attack.  After you perform this attack, the defender receives 1 stress token if its hull value is "4" or lower.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>3</Dice>
			<Range>2-3</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="iontorpedoes">
			<Name>Ion Torpedoes</Name>
			<Cost>5</Cost>
			<Text>Attack (target lock): Spend your target lock and discard this card to perform this attack. If this attack hits, the defender and each ship at Range 1 of it receives 1 ion token.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>4</Dice>
			<Range>2-3</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="bombloadout">
			<Name>Bomb Loadout</Name>
			<Cost>0</Cost>
			<Text>Your upgrade bar gains the {bomb} icon.</Text>
			<Limited>true</Limited>
			<Ship>ywing</Ship>
			<ShipRequirement>Y-Wing</ShipRequirement>
			<AdditionalUpgrades>
				<Upgrade>Bomb</Upgrade>
			</AdditionalUpgrades>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="extramunitions">
			<Name>Extra Munitions</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When you equip this card, place 1 ordnance token on each equipped {torpedo}, {missile}, and {bomb} Upgrade card. When you are instructed to discard an Upgrade card, you may discard 1 ordnance token on that card instead.</Text>
			<Limited>true</Limited>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="plasmatorpedoes">
			<Name>Plasma Torpedoes</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Attack (target lock): Spend your target lock and discard this card to perform this attack.  If this attack hits, after dealing damage, remove 1 shield token from the defender</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>4</Dice>
			<Range>2-3</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
	</Category>
	<Category id="turret" type="Turret Weapon">
		<Upgrade id="ioncannonturret">
			<Name>Ion Cannon Turret</Name>
			<Cost>5</Cost>
			<Text>Attack: Attack 1 ship (even a ship outside your firing arc).  If this attack hits the target ship, the ship suffers 1 damage and receives 1 ion token. Then cancel all dice results.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>3</Dice>
			<Range>1-2</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="blasterturret">
			<Name>Blaster Turret</Name>
			<Cost>4</Cost>
			<Text>Attack (focus): Spend 1 focus token to perform this attack against 1 ship (even a ship outside your firing arc).</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>3</Dice>
			<Range>1-2</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="autoblasterturret">
			<Name>Autoblaster Turret</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>Attack: Attack 1 ship (even a ship outside your firing arc).  Your {hit} results cannot be canceled by defense dice. The defender may cancel {crit} results before {hit} results.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>2</Dice>
			<Range>1</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="twinlaserturret">
			<Name>Twin Laser Turret</Name>
			<Cost>6</Cost>
			<Text>Attack: Perform this attack twice (even against a ship outside your firing arc).  Each time this attack hits, the defender suffers 1 damage. Then cancel all dice results.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>3</Dice>
			<Range>2-3</Range>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="dorsalturret">
			<Name>Dorsal Turret</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>Attack: Attack 1 ship (even a ship outside your firing arc).

If the target of this attack is at Range 1, roll 1 additional attack die.</Text>
			<SecondaryWeapon>true</SecondaryWeapon>
			<Dice>2</Dice>
			<Range>1-2</Range>
			<Preview>true</Preview>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
	</Category>
	<Category id="tech" type="Tech">
		<Upgrade id="weaponsguidance">
			<Name>Weapons Guidance</Name>
			<Cost>2</Cost>
			<Text>When attacking, you may spend a focus token to change one of your blank results to a {hit} result.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
		<Upgrade id="commsrelay">
			<Name>Comm Relay</Name>
			<Cost>3</Cost>
			<Text>You cannot have more than 1 evade token.  During the End phase, do not remove an unused evade token from your ship.</Text>
			<Owned>0</Owned>
		</Upgrade>
	</Category>
</Upgrades>